<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on blijblijblij.github.io</title>
    <link>http://blijblijblij.github.io/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetup on blijblijblij.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 07:00:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blijblijblij.github.io/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pentaho NL spring meetup</title>
      <link>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/pentahanl-spring-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 07:00:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/pentahanl-spring-meetup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last month we gathered for the second Pentaho NL meetup. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/incentro&#34;&gt;@Incentro&lt;/a&gt; were sponsoring the location (their office at former Airport Ypenburg) as well as some excellent food and drinks, much appreciated guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again we had an impressive turn up, some new faces, some more familiar, a good mix for sharing and discussing life, the universe, and well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/pentaho&#34;&gt;Pentaho&lt;/a&gt; stuff&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-virtualization-with-pdi-community-edition:798285d4784124b9be5049549e519cbb&#34;&gt;Data Virtualization with PDI Community Edition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edwin Weber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/c38182b984a7481a01c0b0e84eb3b2e4a926eff7/images/2016-04-19-edwin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Edwin on fire!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edwin challenged the demo-gods, they got the better off him. But Edwin is a master (karate wise, as well as pentaho wise). He reclaimed his mastery and demo-ed Data Virtualization using the thin jdbc driver running sql queries on top of data transformations. Apparently this functionality still needs some hammering to get it to work. But from what I have heared Edwins work has already been relayed to another master, a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/diethardsteiner&#34;&gt;Diethard Steiner&lt;/a&gt; post should be in the makings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/edwin_weber&#34;&gt;Edwins&lt;/a&gt; talk, here is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/raw/0edeaeef6e7778ebac04579505e3418470d3eb91/pdf/20160503_data_virtualization_demo.pdf&#34;&gt;transscript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;datastax-cassandra-plugin:798285d4784124b9be5049549e519cbb&#34;&gt;Datastax Cassandra plugin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rudmer van Dijk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The current Cassandra plugin from Pentaho uses an old driver which is unable to support secure SSL connections to the cluster. At Incentro we created a new plugin that utilises the Datastax driver so we can use the secure connection. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a walkthrough and demonstration of the three steps in this plugin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rudmer gave a demo about their newly developed Data Cassandra driver taking us through all functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/master/images/2016-04-13-cassandra-driver.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;In the marketplace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been released from the marketplace, hooray on that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tips-and-tricks-of-using-javascript-in-pdi:798285d4784124b9be5049549e519cbb&#34;&gt;Tips and Tricks of using JavaScript in PDI&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julien Hofstede&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We all agree: Kettle is awesome. But sometimes seemingly easy things are hard to accomplish, or just not possible with Kettle. I&amp;rsquo;ll show some easy and advanced uses of the JavaScript Step in PDI such as prompts, dynamic accessing of rows, calculations and filtering of rows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien talk was very interesting, stressing the balance between doing it the Etl / pentaho way versus fixing it in one go in a javascript step. The javascript step is a very powerfull step (dating back to that very beginning of PDI) enabling you to dive deep inside the Pentaho data-integration application and exposing api&amp;rsquo;s unknown to most!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His talk can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/raw/master/pdf/20160513_JavaScript%20in%20PDI.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but make sure you dive into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/raw/master/pdf/JavaScript%20in%20PDI.zip&#34;&gt;demo samples&lt;/a&gt; as well!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, another inspriring Pentaho NL meetup!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll boooh, hugo yeah!</title>
      <link>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/jekyll-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 16:13:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/jekyll-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Not that long ago I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/2015-11-16-newblog&#34;&gt;migrated my blog to github pages&lt;/a&gt; using  &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;static website generator&lt;/a&gt;. You write some intermediate &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; pages, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34;&gt;cheat some markup&lt;/a&gt; and the generator will build the static website for you, rss feeds, navigation and the whole shebang included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt; the sm-meister that wrote Jekyll went through some hard, breaking and annoying changes. Probably very sound changes, but I want something that works, takes little effort to maintain, yet slightly more appealing than&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-type=html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;My First Post&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Epic story goes here...&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;enter-hugo:812557afe512b3a4b59c1e5d15e88a2c&#34;&gt;Enter hugo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hugo is great for content-driven websites, because it is completely dependency-free and is easy to get going. What it lacks for in extensibility, it largely makes up for with a good content model and super-fast build times.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another quote I agree on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hugo is quite possibly the easiest to install software you’ve ever used, simply download and run. Hugo doesn’t depend on administrative privileges, databases, runtimes, interpreters or external libraries. Sites built with Hugo can be deployed on S3, GitHub Pages, Dropbox or any web host.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll take it, after some hurdles migrated this blog into a Hugo-i-fied one, and yet again ready for blogging incontinence&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/11/static-website-generators-jekyll-middleman-roots-hugo-review/&#34;&gt;article on the battle of the static site generators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;download hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/quickstart/&#34;&gt;getting started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just my 2 cents, regards, Rogier&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: First pentaho nl meetup!</title>
      <link>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/2016-04-26-first-meetup-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 23:03:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/2016-04-26-first-meetup-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tools-dashboards-are-awesome:c9a0adf7a1a73d196ca2608ce478d205&#34;&gt;Tools Dashboards are Awesome!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julien Hofstede&lt;/em&gt; This presentation showed some techniques to make development of the dashboards easier like reusable components and global settings. And even to create your own component! Take the step beyond CDE and leverage the full power of CDF! No knowledge or experience with CDF? No worries! It will for sure help you to understand the concept of CDF better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien also demo-ed a lot, styling a set of components in an instant just by implementing a standard layout, and reusing that in several graphs extending that standard layout!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/blijblijblij.github.io/blob/master/pdf/20160131_CDF_beyond_CDE.pdf&#34;&gt;Juliens talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First pentaho nl meetup!</title>
      <link>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/2016-01-30-first-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 23:02:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blijblijblij.github.io/post/2016-01-30-first-meetup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Busy times, so with a slight delay a recap of our very first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Pentaho-NL-Meetup/&#34;&gt;pentaho NL meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ReelMetrics supplied a nice venue for this first meetup, took care off much appreciated beers and pizza&amp;rsquo;s. After these refreshments we had some nice talks covering a wide range of functionalities within the Pentaho ecosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro:eeaa397aca5e1bb7cca39c6e05f576ee&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a yearly gathering somewhere in Europe, why not do a dutch equivalent every couple of months?! As open-source is thriving, community initiatives become even more important, and more than enough people doing Pentaho stuff in The Netherlands, so we gave it a try!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some general &amp;ldquo;goals&amp;rdquo; to our meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to have FUN!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to learn!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to share!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for noobs, super-dupper-master-hackers and everything in between!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every couple of months-ish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;, if a traveling pentaho rockstars comes along, we should do a adhoc meetup
and seize that opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pentaho-and-docker-docker-docker:eeaa397aca5e1bb7cca39c6e05f576ee&#34;&gt;Pentaho and Docker Docker Docker!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rogier Wessel&lt;/em&gt; Ok, I must admit, I am a big fan of both Pentaho and Docker. During this talk I explained
first the basic building blocks that make up docker. Then talked about glueing
services together into a docker composition. Finally once you start growing that
infrastructure other problems arise, orchestration of docker instances running
on multiple hosts gets complicated, and running a couple compositions doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut
it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gathered a lot of direction on orchestration based on the sound analyses by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/adrianmouat&#34;&gt;Adrian Mouat&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; article on O&amp;rsquo;reilly radar &lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2015/10/swarm-v-fleet-v-kubernetes-v-mesos.html&#34;&gt;Swarm v. Fleet v. Kubernetes v. Mesos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on that article I continued my quest in orchestration and investigated &lt;a href=&#34;http://mesos.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache Mesos&lt;/a&gt;
extensively. The second half of my talk was demo time. When you do Docker with Pentaho software on Apache mesos, what are the components that make up the infrastructure, how is everything interconnected, and why does this complicated infrastructure make sense once your infrastructure grows beyond a certain size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qcNw-m7f7XHjGA6KfEjd3mqR03gsqM2N6kNDCTgP5pA/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All code about creating and running a Mesos cluster is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/docker-mesos&#34;&gt;my github page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/docker-mesos/blob/develop/create/create-virtualbox-cluster.sh&#34;&gt;building a local virtualbox cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/docker-mesos/blob/develop/create/create-generic-ssh-cluster.sh&#34;&gt;building a cluster via ssh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/docker-mesos/blob/develop/create/create-aws-cluster.sh&#34;&gt;or directly via the aws api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blijblijblij/docker-mesos/tree/develop/run&#34;&gt;and running that cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ctools-dashboards-are-awesome:eeaa397aca5e1bb7cca39c6e05f576ee&#34;&gt;CTools Dashboards are Awesome!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Julien Hofstede&lt;/em&gt; This presentation showed some techniques to make development of the dashboards easier like reusable components and global settings. And even to create your own component! Take the step beyond CDE and leverage the full power of CDF! No knowledge or experience with CDF? No worries! It will for sure help you to understand the concept of CDF better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien also demo-ed a lot, styling a set of components in an instant just by implementing a standard layout, and reusing that in several graphs extending that standard layout!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-community-contributed-jdbc-metadata-step-for-pentaho-data-integration:eeaa397aca5e1bb7cca39c6e05f576ee&#34;&gt;The Community Contributed JDBC Metadata Step for Pentaho Data integration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roland Bouman&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rpbouman/pentaho-pdi-plugin-jdbc-metadata&#34;&gt;The Community Contributed JDBC Metadata Step for Pentaho Data integration&lt;/a&gt; enables you to use database metadata to drive transformations. You can use it to track database schema changes, to generate DDL, and even to implement datawarehouse automation. His presentation demonstrated the features of the plugin and illustrated how you can use it in your kettle transformations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roland never seems to stop coming up with new functionalities giving new insights, his code is all up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rpbouman&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. He could do with some extra eyes on the code, or some extra code to further extent his current work. So feel free to join and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rolandbouman&#34;&gt;give him a nudge&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-s-up-next:eeaa397aca5e1bb7cca39c6e05f576ee&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s up next?!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, a lot of people turned up, some even took a hotel because of their long travels, big up for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to ReelMetrics some other sponsors came forward, for a location, pitch in for some beers :-). Also several people already offered to give a talk about some subject. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dennisintgroen&#34;&gt;Dennis&lt;/a&gt; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind diving into CDE widgets, and offering another view to reusable components along the lines of Juliens talk. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/edwin_weber&#34;&gt;Edwin&lt;/a&gt; had something up his sleeve. Even [Dan Keeley]&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/codek1&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/codek1&lt;/a&gt; offered to come over and give a talk, we would love to accept his offer, and learn from his extensive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enough momentum, looking forward to our next meetup!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>