<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meetup on blog.blijblijblij.com</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/tags/meetup/</link><description>Recent content in meetup on blog.blijblijblij.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &lt;a href="https://github.com/blijblijblij">Rogier Wessel&lt;/a> 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:29:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.blijblijblij.com/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PentahoNL meetup March 2017 recap</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2017-03-17-pentahonl-recap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:29:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2017-03-17-pentahonl-recap/</guid><description>Great vibe, interesting talks We had another great PentahoNL meetup last week.
This session was hosted by Rob Smienk at the offices of @MRDM in Deventer. @MRDM is a company specialized in aggregating Medical data and registration data to gather better insights in Medical processes and treatment outcomes.
Hospitals and University Medical Centers increasingly need to report and clarify on Costs and Quality of medical treatments. They gather data from connected Hospitals, aggregate and benchmark the results.</description></item><item><title>Pentaho NL spring meetup</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/pentahanl-spring-meetup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 07:00:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/pentahanl-spring-meetup/</guid><description>Last month we gathered for the second Pentaho NL meetup. @Incentro were sponsoring the location (their office at former Airport Ypenburg) as well as some excellent food and drinks, much appreciated guys!
Again we had an impressive turn up, some new faces, some more familiar, a good mix for sharing and discussing life, the universe, and well, Pentaho stuff&amp;hellip;
Data Virtualization with PDI Community Edition Edwin Weber
Edwin challenged the demo-gods, they got the better off him.</description></item><item><title>Jekyll boooh, hugo yeah!</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/jekyll-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 16:13:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/jekyll-to-hugo/</guid><description>Not that long ago I migrated my blog to github pages using Jekyll. Jekyll is a static website generator. You write some intermediate markdown pages, cheat some markup and the generator will build the static website for you, rss feeds, navigation and the whole shebang included.
BUT the sm-meister that wrote Jekyll went through some hard, breaking and annoying changes. Probably very sound changes, but I want something that works, takes little effort to maintain, yet slightly more appealing than</description></item><item><title>Update: First pentaho nl meetup!</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2016-04-26-first-meetup-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 23:03:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2016-04-26-first-meetup-update/</guid><description>Tools Dashboards are Awesome! Julien Hofstede This presentation showed some techniques to make development of the dashboards easier like reusable components and global settings. And even to create your own component! Take the step beyond CDE and leverage the full power of CDF! No knowledge or experience with CDF? No worries! It will for sure help you to understand the concept of CDF better.
Julien also demo-ed a lot, styling a set of components in an instant just by implementing a standard layout, and reusing that in several graphs extending that standard layout!</description></item><item><title>First pentaho nl meetup!</title><link>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2016-01-30-first-meetup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 23:02:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.blijblijblij.com/posts/2016-01-30-first-meetup/</guid><description>Busy times, so with a slight delay a recap of our very first pentaho NL meetup.
ReelMetrics supplied a nice venue for this first meetup, took care off much appreciated beers and pizza's. After these refreshments we had some nice talks covering a wide range of functionalities within the Pentaho ecosphere.
Intro From a yearly gathering somewhere in Europe, why not do a dutch equivalent every couple of months?! As open-source is thriving, community initiatives become even more important, and more than enough people doing Pentaho stuff in The Netherlands, so we gave it a try!</description></item></channel></rss>